MARIAM DARCHIASHVILI

Graphic Designer

ABOUT:

Avid graphic designer and visual artist, with a degree in Graphic Design from The Royal Academy of Arts, The Hague (KABK). An organised hard-worker and quick-learner; with interests in typography, printed matter and curation, but always open for a new experience. My inspiration lays in music, senses, language, philosophy and dark aesthetics, which I often try to incorporate in my work both theoretically and visually.

Believer in power of black, reason and beauty of Classical Art

LANGUAGES:

- Georgian (Native)
- English (Fluent)
- Russian (Fluent)
- French (Basic understanding)

SKILLS:

- Honesty
- Fluent communicative and organisational skills with the capacity for collaboration and critical reflection.
- Fluent in use of most Adobe software, such as - Illustrator, InDesign, Photoshop, Premiere Pro, Audition and After Effects. Proficient in use of Glyphs.
- Handy with techniques of Riso printing, silkscreening and letterpress.
- Intermediate use of HTML and CSS languages. As well as having basic knowledge of Unity and Blender.

CONTACTS:

The Netherlands

+31 (0) 6 245 09 969 komnen.info@gmail.com www.komnen.com www.behance.net/Komnen

EDUCATION:

British Higher School of Art and Design

/Art&Design Pre-Foundation

September 2013 - May 2014, Moscow

Royal Academy of Art (KABK)

/ Graphic Design (BA)

September 2014 - June 2019, The Hague, The Netherlands

Stefan Schäfer Design & Research Studio

/Internship

September 2018 - November 2018, Amsterdam, The Netherlands

EXPERIENCE:

FREELANCE DESIGNER FOR GD HOLDING

/Design

April 2018 - present, Tbilisi

AMNESTY INTERNATIONAL - DUTCH 50TH ANNIVERSARY - GROUP EXHIBITION

/Design and Communication

April 2018, Amsterdam, Amsterdam Theatre

For a celebration of it's 50th anniversary, Amnesty Netherlands worked with KABK on creating a set of installations, researching and visualising some of their hardest cases.

DON'T MIND THE WALLS - A POSTER FOR AN EXHIBITION OF KABK FINE ARTS

/Design and Communication

April 2018, The Hague, KABK

Don't Mind the walls was an exhibition organised by the 2d year Sculpture students of the Fine Arts Department of KABK.

BITS&PIECES - A WEEKLY NEWSLETTER FOR KABK FINE ARTS

/Design and Communication

September 2017 - May 2018, The Hague, KABK

B&P is a weekly newsletter for Fine Arts students, that contains information of upcoming classes and events. Responsibility: design and sending out.

KABK FINE ARTS OPEN DAY DESIGN

/Design

January 2018, The Hague, KABK

Design of the Open Day identity for the Fine Arts department and it's navigation. Included: event posters, exhibition information, navigational signs and same-day event flyers.

CONSOLIDATING SOUND AND IMAGE

/Lecture/Workshop

October 2017, Moscow, Sfera Education

VISUAL IDENTITY FOR SFERA EDUCATION

/Desigr

September 2017 - present, Moscow, Sfera education

BALANCE BY STRUGGLE

/Curating and Designing an exhibition

September 2017, The Hague, Gemeentemuseum

Balance by Struggle - is an exhibition organised in the framework of celebration of 100 years of De Stijl movement by The Hague City Hall and The Royal Academy of Art. Me, Yeon Sung and Dominika Fojtikova conceptualised and curated an exhibtion in the walls of Gemeentemuseum. More details are online.